<Recipe><Header><Name>French Macarons</Name><Author>The Blisery</Author><Date/><Source>http://www.theblissery.com/2014/08/french-macarons-recipe/</Source></Header><Description>Macarons. Need I say More?!</Description><Ingredients><Item><Item>egg whites</Item><Amount>2 oz</Amount></Item></Ingredients><Directions><Step>Combine granulated sugar and almond flour in food processor, pulsed to a fine powder. Sift.</Step><Step>Add food coloring to egg whites and desolve.</Step><Step>Combine eggwhites and almond mixture &#x2013; with a spatula you want to push them together until a cohesive paste is made.</Step><Step>You want to go a little dark on the food coloring as it will fade when the meringue is added.</Step><Step>In a stand mixer, combine fresh egg whites, pinch of sugar, and dried egg white powder.</Step><Step>Begin to whip on low-medium speed.</Step><Step>In a non reactive pot, combine sugar and water together &#x2013; first bring this mixture to a simmer until it reaches 230 degrees fahrenheit.</Step><Step>When the temperature has reached, turn stand mixer on high speed.</Step><Step>When your sugar mixture reaches 240 degrees, your eggwhites should be at a soft/medium peak.</Step><Step>When your sugar reaches 244 degrees, remove from heat and slowly stream in to eggwhites, between the whip and bowl.</Step><Step>Stream until completely combined.</Step><Step>Keep whipping until the Italian Meringue reaches aproximately 90 degrees.</Step><Step>Remove from stand mixer.</Step><Step>Slowly fold and push the meringue into the almond mixture, turning and folding until completely assimilated. (It is arguable that this is the only situation in baking where you want to somewhat deflate your meringue, slowly pushing the air out of it.)</Step><Step>Keep pushing and folding until you reach a stage where your mixture begins to slowly run to the sides of the bowl.</Step><Step>Lift your spatula up with a little mixture still running off. (The mixture should ribbon back, not liquidy, not too thick. Just right.)</Step><Step>Pour your mixture into your piping bag.</Step><Step>Begin to slowly pipe 1 inch thick circles onto your silpat lined sheet tray or parchment. (A great way to achieve perfect circles are to slowly apply pressure to the top of the bag until you reach disired amount, and twirl the tip of the bag around the circle, creating a seamless circle.)</Step><Step>Tap your completed tray on your counter 2-3 times to push out air bubbles. (If any air bubbles remain, take a toothpick and gently pop all bubbles.)</Step><Step>Immediately place your tray into preheated oven, 11-12 minutes!</Step><Step>Lift your macarons off the tray gently, until it pops off.</Step><Step>You can sandwhich your macarons with anything you&#x2019;d like, a simple jam is great, a nice buttercream, simple almond butter is great, chocolate ganache is decadent.</Step></Directions></Recipe>
