<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Recipe>
	<Header>
		<Name>
			Lemon Creme Brulee
		</Name>
		<Author>
			Renee Nicole
		</Author>
		<Date>
			13.10.2016
		</Date>
		<Source>
			http://reneenicoleskitchen.com/lemon-creme-brulee/
		</Source>
	</Header>
	<Description>
		Lemon Creme Brulee is my ideal Valentine’s Day dessert. A thick creamy texture with a light lemony essence. Serve with strawberries and champagne!
	</Description>
	<Ingredients>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				brown sugar
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				3 TBSP
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				egg yolks
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				4
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				zest of 2 medium sized lemons
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				vanilla extract
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				1/2 tsp
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				pinch of salt
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				1
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				heavy whipping cream
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				1 1/2 cups
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				half & half
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				1/2
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				white sugar - divided
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				5 TBSP
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				strawberries for garnish
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				
			</Amount>
		</Item>
	</Ingredients>
	<Directions>
		<Step>
			Boil hot water, preferably in a tea kettle for easy pouring.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Heat oven to 300 degrees.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Zest lemons and separate egg yolks from the whites.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Whisk together brown sugar, egg yolks, lemon zest, vanilla, and salt in a medium sized bowl.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Bring cream, half & half, and 3 TBSP of white sugar to a simmer over medium heat. Takes about 5 minutes. Stir occasionally and do not let it boil.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Slowly pour the warmed cream into the egg yolk mixture, while whisking constantly. Pouring too fast will result in scrambled eggs.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Allow to sit for 5 minutes to draw the lemon oil out of the zest.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Strain mixture into a large measuring cup with a pour spout. Squeeze as much of liquid as possible from the lemon zest with the back of the spoon.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Place your 4 ramekins into a 9x9 inch pan. Divide the custard mixture into the ramekins.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Pour the boiling water into the pan until it's between 1/2 and 3/4 of the way up the side of the ramekins. Careful not to pour water into the custard.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Cover with heavy duty aluminum foil and bake 30 - 35 minutes or until centers are set.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Cool to room temperature then refrigerate for a minimum of three hours.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Cover each ramekin with 1 1/2 tsp of white sugar, adjusting for ramekin width as needed.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Brulee the tops with a kitchen torch or under the broiler - checking every minute or so.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Serve with strawberries and champagne.
		</Step>
	</Directions>
</Recipe>