<Recipe>
	<Header>
		<Name>
			Raspberry Rose Souffé
		</Name>
		<Author>
			Ben O'Donoghue and Curtis Stone
		</Author>
		<Date>
			13.10.2016
		</Date>
		<Source>
			https://food52.com/recipes/13062-raspberry-rose-souffle
		</Source>
	</Header>
	<Description>
		Adapted from Almost Bourdain's Lemon, Lime and Orange Soufflé, original recipe from Raspberry Souffle in Serving The Menu Again by Ben O'Donoghue and Curtis Stone.
	</Description>
	<Ingredients>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				6 ounces containers of fresh raspberries
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				4
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				ounces castor sugar
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				3 1/2
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				tablespoons corn flour
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				4
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				egg whites (room temperature)
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				10
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				pinch of salt
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				1
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				teaspoon rose water
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				1
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				ounces castor sugar
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				3 1/2
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				6 ounces butter, softened, enough to grease the mould
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				7
			</Amount>
		</Item>
				<Item>
			<Name>
				ounces caster sugar, enough to coat the moulds
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				3 1/2
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				Icing sugar, for dusting
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				
			</Amount>
		</Item>
		<Item>
			<Name>
				Creme anglaise or ice cream, to serve
			</Name>
			<Amount>
				
			</Amount>
		</Item>
	</Ingredients>
	<Directions>
		<Step>
			Puree the raspberries in a blender and press through a fine sieve to remove the seeds. Add enough water to make 500 milliliters of puree.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			To make the base, place the raspberry puree and sugar in a saucepan over a medium heat. Stir to dissolve the sugar and bring to the boil. Mix the corn flour with just enough water to make a smooth paste. Once the fruit puree reaches boiling point, reduce the heat to low and whisk the corn flour paste into the fruit puree a little at a time. Whisk for 1 minute and do not allow mixture to boil again. Remove from the heat and set aside. Chill to cool completely.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Preheat the oven to 180°C/350°F.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Place the egg whites into a very clean, very large mixing bowl, add the salt and beat at high speed until soft peaks form. Add the sugar, a little at a time, and beat until stiff peaks form. Do not over whisk or the egg whites will break down and be unable to hold the air required to life the souffle.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Place the fruit puree base into a very large bowl and whisk until smooth. Add a little of the egg white mixture and stir in to loosen the consistency. Gently fold in the remaining egg white and rose essence.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Brush the bases of 6 1-cup capacity ramekins with the softened butter, then, using upward strokes (this is very important), brush the sides. Chill in the refrigerator until set, and then repeat. Sprinkle in a little of the caster sugar, turning the ramekins to coat the base and sides. To fill the moulds, use a palette knife to spread the souffle mixture around the sides while holding the ramekin at a 45-degrees angle. Fill the middle and smooth top top, without allowing any mixture to stick to the rim or run over the sides.
		</Step>
		<Step>
			Place in the oven and bake for 12-14 minutes or until golden and well risen. Serve immediately dusted with icing sugar, and with creme anglaise or ice cream on the side, if you like.
		</Step>
	</Directions>
</Recipe>